<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Quantum Measurement Theory - Tag - Haifei&#39;s Home</title>
        <link>http://example.com/tags/quantum-measurement-theory/</link>
        <description>Quantum Measurement Theory - Tag - Haifei&#39;s Home</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hfwang132@gmail.com (hfwang132)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>hfwang132@gmail.com (hfwang132)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:49:27 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/quantum-measurement-theory/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>The Collapsed State of Position Measurement</title>
    <link>http://example.com/position_measurement/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:49:27 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/position_measurement/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Common sense tells us that an actual position measurement will not produce a delta function, as the delta function itself is pathological. So what should the collapsed state of an actual position measurement look like?
TL;DR:
Let the wave function of the system to be measured be $\varphi(x)$, then the collapsed wave function is:
$\varphi^{(q)}(x) = \mathcal{A}\psi(q-gx) \varphi(x)$
where $\psi(x)$ is the initial wave function of the instrument&rsquo;s pointer. $q$ is the reading of the instrument&rsquo;s pointer.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Difference Between Quantum Entanglement and Classical Correlation, and the Quantum Measurement Problem</title>
    <link>http://example.com/classical_correlation/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:33:11 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/classical_correlation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Many physicists use an example to explain quantum entanglement to the public:
Imagine you have two boxes, one containing pizza and the other a burger. Before opening the boxes, you cannot know what is inside. Alice and Bob each take a box and move to distant locations. When Alice opens her box, she instantly knows what is in Bob&rsquo;s box far away.
This example must be wrong&hellip; because it doesn&rsquo;t involve quantum mechanics at all.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>POVM: a brief introduction</title>
    <link>http://example.com/povm/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 02:22:12 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/povm/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Projection Measurement Traditionally, a measurement, in the sense of Von Neumann, is a series of projection operators. By performing spectral decomposition on the self-adjoint operator corresponding to the observable, denoted as $ O = \sum_i \lambda_i |\varphi_i\rangle\langle\varphi_i| $, we obtain these projection operators $ |\varphi_i\rangle\langle\varphi_i| $. This part is well-known to students who have studied elementary quantum mechanics.
Besides the Von Neumann measurement, there is a more general type of measurement called Generalized Measurements or Positive Operator Valued Measures (POVMs).]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
