<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Storage/Partition - Tag - Haifei&#39;s Home</title>
        <link>http://example.com/tags/storage/partition/</link>
        <description>Storage/Partition - Tag - Haifei&#39;s Home</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hfwang132@gmail.com (hfwang132)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>hfwang132@gmail.com (hfwang132)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/storage/partition/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Increasing the swapfile for Linux</title>
    <link>http://example.com/increase_swapfile/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:59:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/increase_swapfile/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Xilinx&rsquo;s toolchain consumes soooo much memory! Sometimes it causes the system to freeze&hellip; After all, my laptop only has 8GB of RAM. So there&rsquo;s no other choice but to add virtual memories.
After increase the swapfile, the system performance has improved a lot:
1 2 3 4 sudo swapoff /swapfile sudo dd if=/dev/zero of=/swapfile bs=1M count=16384 sudo mkswap /swapfile sudo swapon /swapfile ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Partitioning and formatting SD cards on Linux</title>
    <link>http://example.com/linux_sd_card/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:43:36 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/linux_sd_card/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[To partition and format an SD card in Linux, follow these steps: First, connect the SD card to your PC. Then, use the fdisk command in the bash command line to partition the SD card. Finally, use the mkfs command to create a file system (format) on the SD card.
The main commands are as follows:
First, use sudo fdisk -l to confirm which device in /dev corresponds to the SD card.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Mounting the EFI partition in Windows OS</title>
    <link>http://example.com/efi_partition/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:26:16 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/efi_partition/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[To mount the EFI partitions, run the following commands in PowerShell:
1 2 3 4 5 6 diskpart list disk # make sure which is the disk that contains the EFI partition. usually 0 select disk 0 list partition # make sure which is the EFI partition. normally 0 select disk 0 assign letter=z Then we will mount the EFI partition as drive Z.
This operation may be useful when using a dual-boot system with Windows and Ubuntu: Sometimes, after removing the Ubuntu system, only the Windows system remains, but the GRUB interface still appears every time the computer boots.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
