<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Quantum Information - Category - Haifei&#39;s Home</title>
        <link>http://example.com/categories/quantum-information/</link>
        <description>Quantum Information - Category - Haifei&#39;s Home</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hfwang132@gmail.com (hfwang132)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>hfwang132@gmail.com (hfwang132)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 18:36:47 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.com/categories/quantum-information/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Does the idle light passing through the optical fiber amplifier still entangle with the signal light?</title>
    <link>http://example.com/spdc_optical_amp/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 18:36:47 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/spdc_optical_amp/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Does the idle light passing through the optical fiber amplifier still entangle with the signal light, which is produced by SPDC?
Let&rsquo;s consider two extremes:
Extreme 1: The gain of the amplifier is equal to 1, that is, there is no gain at all.
In this case, the amplifier acts as if it has done nothing and is an identity channel. So, of course, the entanglement will still be maintained. (Actually, it&rsquo;s not necessarily the case.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Does the Speed of Quantum Entanglement Exceed the Speed of Light?</title>
    <link>http://example.com/contextuality/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 18:34:24 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/contextuality/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Too long; didn&rsquo;t read version:
&ldquo;Spooky action at a distance (superluminal)&rdquo; is an outdated view. According to special relativity, there is no interaction between events at spacelike separation. The mainstream view in academia is to consider quantum states and measurement bases together as reality, known as contextuality. Nonlocality is a corollary of contextuality.
Body:
Discussing the &ldquo;speed&rdquo; of quantum entanglement is meaningless.
If the distance between two measurement events a and b is spacelike, then a is neither in the past nor in the future of b.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Collapsed State of Position Measurement</title>
    <link>http://example.com/position_measurement/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:49:27 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/position_measurement/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Common sense tells us that an actual position measurement will not produce a delta function, as the delta function itself is pathological. So what should the collapsed state of an actual position measurement look like?
TL;DR:
Let the wave function of the system to be measured be $\varphi(x)$, then the collapsed wave function is:
$\varphi^{(q)}(x) = \mathcal{A}\psi(q-gx) \varphi(x)$
where $\psi(x)$ is the initial wave function of the instrument&rsquo;s pointer. $q$ is the reading of the instrument&rsquo;s pointer.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How Are Creation and Annihilation Operators Derived?</title>
    <link>http://example.com/annilation_op/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:47:25 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/annilation_op/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The motivation for defining creation and annihilation operators is simple and can be entirely derived from classical mechanics.
Think about how we solve the classical harmonic oscillator. Since position and momentum are coupled:
$\begin{cases} \frac{\mathrm{d}x}{\mathrm{d}t} = \omega p \\ \frac{\mathrm{d}p}{\mathrm{d}t} = -\omega x \end{cases}$
That is,
$\frac{\mathrm{d}}{\mathrm{d}t} \begin{bmatrix} x \\ p \end{bmatrix} = \begin{bmatrix} 0 &amp; \omega \\ -\omega &amp; 0 \end{bmatrix} \begin{bmatrix} x \\ p \end{bmatrix}$
So, we just need to decouple them.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A Simple Quantum Description of Lasers</title>
    <link>http://example.com/laser_quantum/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:42:31 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/laser_quantum/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This article aims to derive the coherent state of a laser from basic quantum dynamics.
Consider the interaction between a two-level system and a single-mode light field, where the frequency of the light field equals the energy level difference.
The two-level system initially starts in the excited state $|e\rangle$, and the light field is in the vacuum state $|0\rangle$.
According to the Jaynes-Cummings model, even if the light field is in the vacuum state, spontaneous emission will occur.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Orbital Angular Momentum of Photons</title>
    <link>http://example.com/oam/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:35:05 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/oam/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Preface A paper published in PRA in 1992 [1] pointed out that photons also have orbital angular momentum (OAM). Compared to spin angular momentum (i.e., polarization, SAM) which can only take $\pm \hbar$, orbital angular momentum can take any integer multiple of $\hbar$. Such orbital angular momentum can be carried by helical wavefronts.
You might be surprised: did people only discover this in 1992? In fact, helical wavefronts had been studied before 1992; photons carrying angular momentum greater than $\hbar$ had already been predicted by atomic physics (though they originate from higher-order transition processes, which do not satisfy the selection rules and thus have very low probabilities, making them practically unobservable in experiments).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Difference Between Quantum Entanglement and Classical Correlation, and the Quantum Measurement Problem</title>
    <link>http://example.com/classical_correlation/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:33:11 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/classical_correlation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Many physicists use an example to explain quantum entanglement to the public:
Imagine you have two boxes, one containing pizza and the other a burger. Before opening the boxes, you cannot know what is inside. Alice and Bob each take a box and move to distant locations. When Alice opens her box, she instantly knows what is in Bob&rsquo;s box far away.
This example must be wrong&hellip; because it doesn&rsquo;t involve quantum mechanics at all.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Quantum state tomography - a beginner&#39;s guide</title>
    <link>http://example.com/state_tomography/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 15:06:14 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/state_tomography/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Quantum State Tomography Quantum state tomography is the process of deducing the [quantum state] based on the [results of measurements on a quantum state ensemble]. Its formulation is straightforward, as follows:
Given a series of measurement operators ${\Pi_1, \ldots, \Pi_n}$ and their corresponding measurement probabilities $p_k = \operatorname{Tr}[\rho \Pi_k]$, find the quantum state $\rho$.
In other words, in these $n$ equations $p_k = \operatorname{Tr}[\rho \Pi_k]$, given $p_k$ and $\Pi_k$, find $\rho$.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Probing the spectral purity with unheralded g2 measurements in HBT experiment</title>
    <link>http://example.com/hbt_spectral_correlation/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 02:22:34 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/hbt_spectral_correlation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the previous section, we discussed the principle of measuring the quantum second-order correlation function with a non-photon-number-resolving single-photon detector in the HBT experiment.
https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/679453473
In this section, let&rsquo;s see what the quantum second-order correlation function is used for. In addition to the common uses such as distinguishing between super-Poissonian statistics/Poissonian statistics/sub-Poissonian statistics and distinguishing between photon bunching/anti-bunching, the HBT experiment can also be used to measure the spectral purity of multimode squeezed states.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Probing g2 with non-photon-number-resolving detectors</title>
    <link>http://example.com/hbt_g2/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 02:22:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>hfwang132</author>
    <guid>http://example.com/hbt_g2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[HBT Experiment Those who have conducted quantum optics experiments must be familiar with the Hanbury Brown and Twiss (HBT) experiment, which can be used to measure the second-order correlation function g2. In this experiment, a beam of light is split into two using a 50:50 beamsplitter, and then each beam is detected separately by two detectors. The correlation of the intensities on both sides is measured as a function of delay, as shown in the figure below:]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
